

mr MILENA ŠOŠIĆ
mathematics & programming
milena.sosic@gmail.com
Nikodima Milaša 8/75
Belgrade, Serbia
phone: +381 64 30 55 705

GENERAL:

Machine Learning expert with eighteen years of experience in software development and machine learning algorithm development and implementation. Worked on high-visibility projects in the commercial, banking and telecommunication areas. PhD candidate at Mathematics Faculty, University of Belgrade, computer science department, NLP specialization

OBJECTIVE:

To increase my professional career in the field of machine learning field and software development in general

EDUCATION:

Faculty of Mathematics
University of Belgrade
Computer Science
2020 – current

PhD candidate in computer science, machine learning field, NLP specialization

Faculty of Mathematics University of Belgrade Computer Science 2004 – 2010 Magister degree in Computer Science, thesis: "Applying classification methods on N-gram genome analysis", defended on 2nd of December 2010, average grade 10 out of 10, specialization in relational database architecture and data mining

Faculty of Mathematics University of Belgrade Computer Science 1997 – 2004 University of Belgrade, Graduated Mathematician for Computer Science, graduated on 6th of April 2004, average grade 8,86 out of 10.0

High school "Požarevačka Gimnazija" Department for mathematics 1993 – 1997 Excellent student, "Vuk Karadžić" certificate

Music school "Stevan Mokranjac" Department for flute 1993 – 1997 Excellent student

COMPUTER SKILLS:

general: Machine learning, information system architecture and

optimization, algorithms, OO concepts, database

architecture

programming languages: Python, C#, C++, C, Java, JavaScript, SQL

databases: MS SQL Server, Oracle, DB2

machine learning tools: Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, PyTorch, SPSS, STATISTICA, Weka,

IBM Intelligent Miner

courses: • Machine Learning, Stanford, Coursera

Deep Learning Specialization (containing 5 courses)

Natural Language Processing Specialization (containing 4

courses)

• Learn Python Programming Masterclass, Udemy

Understanding and Visualizing Data with Python,

Coursera

ITIL V3 Foundations (IT Service Management);

Introduction to R, edX

Honor Code Certificate for Programming with C#, edX

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

January 2021 – current Senior Data Scientist GridDynamics With responsibilities to:

- Mentor data science interns and interview candidates
- Develop PoC solutions for R&D projects by exploring the most advanced AI techniques and tools
- Design and implement new solutions with focus on predictive analytics
- Run projects in NLP domain using newest machine learning technologies

February 2019 – January 2021 Al Team Lead Devtech With activities related to:

- Lead AI team, mentor and drive AI efforts
- Develop PoC solutions for existing and past projects by adding AI components
- Design and implement new solutions with focus on predictive analytics
- Run projects in text and sequence analysis domain using newest machine learning technologies

February 2020 – current Advisory Board Member Serbian Al Society Serbian AI Society is being launched in Serbia by the most prominent people in artificial intelligence, with one goal networking and strengthening the domestic AI scene. The aim of this organization is to bring together all stakeholders dealing with this subject which will contribute to the presence and growth of artificial intelligence in Serbia

January 2016 – February 2019 Machine Learning Team Lead Selerant Work on the projects in the PLM area, in the machine learning field, especially:

- Lead a team of software developers
- Responsible for business intelligence applications and systems
- Manage projects using agile methodology
- Manage state-of-the-art machine learning tasks for text segmentation and classification
- Shape product features according to the market requirements
- Cross-functional communication and coordination

December 2013 – January 2016

Data Scientist
Telenor

Work on the high-visibility projects in the banking and telecommunication areas. Utilize analytical tools like IBM SPSS and STATISTICA to identify trends and relationships between different pieces of data, draw appropriate conclusions and translate analytical findings into risk management and marketing strategies that drive value. Especially:

- Develops different up-sell, cross-sell and churn models
- Supports risk models development
- Accountable for segmentation, customer lifetime value calculation
- Supports campaign launches by data preparation, extraction and reporting of results
- Supports customer data mart development

December 2009 – December 2013 Solutions Analyst PepsiCo Manage software solutions within the company with focus on SAP change improvement process, precisely taking following responsibilities:

- SAP change management and analysis in the FICO/COMM/OPS/BI domains
- Functional Specification Design
- Business process analysis and optimization
- SAP security and control activities

January 2007 – December 2009 Senior software developer in .NET Dominion Voting Systems Corporation Maintain, develop and manage different types of software solutions for electronic voting purpose using .NET tools and techniques

August 2004 – January 2007 Develop new software solutions using .NET technology and C# programming language tools with main focus on

SDD ITG software development for RFID readers

LANGUAGES: English – fluent, written and spoken;

Serbian – mother-tongue

PERSONAL CHARACTERISTICS: Born in Pozarevac, Serbia, 7.VI 1978, organizational,

documenting, communicative skills, precise, perspective, hardworking, responsible, ambitious, energetic, reliable, efficient in complying with job requirements, capable for:

Fast learning

• Adjusting to new circumstances

• Both individual and team work

To work under pressure and with time restrictions

HOBBIES: Hiking, reading, playing flute